The last lecture I set up routing, now I want to improve this and I want to make sure that when I click on
Bunu kantlayacak kimseyi ynlendirmeyen son ders ve bunu tkladmda emir
continue in that modal here on the order summary, that I actually load a different route.
zetinde bu modda devam etmeyi ve aslnda farkl bir rota yklediinden emin olmak istiyorum.
Now it's the purchaseContinuedHandler here which is interesting,
imdi ilgin olan bir yl hnndler'e kovalamaca devam ediyor.
that is the handler which gets fired when I click continue.
Baba, devam et dmesini tkladmda kovulan ileyici.
Right now this is where I set loading to true and where I then place my order and send it to the web,
u an burada doru yklemeyi syledim ve sipariimi verdim ve web'e gnderdim.
I will comment all this code out because I no longer want to store it on firebase immediately here
Btn bu kodlar aklayacam, nk buradaki kodu dorudan ate bariyerinde depolamak istemiyorum.
I went to go to the checkout component instead.
Bunun yerine kontrol bileenine gittim.
Now as you learned since burger builder is part of the routable area of our project, we have
tm alanlarna giden yolun bir paras olduundan, eleme yeri ve gemii sahne alanna eriebiliriz.
access to the match location and history props.
Artk rendiiniz gibi, Burgard Boulder projemizin
I can prove this by adding console log this.props in component
Bunu, Konsole bileenine bu sahne kilidini ekleyerek ispatlayabilirim.
DidMount. We have a look,
MT Bir gz atn.
we see the props with history location and match.
Gemiin konumu ve elemesi ile ilgili sorunu gryoruz.
Now by the way, since in here we also use a couple of components like the burger component, just in case
Bu arada, burada merak ettiiniz durumda krk bileen gibi birka bileeni de kullanyoruz
you're wondering, do we also have access to these props here?
nk burada bu sahalara da eriebiliyoruz.
Let's simply log props in the burger function, the burger component,
Bergere bileenindeki sahne takmlarn sadece Bergere ilevi iinde kilitleyelim.
there you see we only have the ingredients.
Gryorsunuz ki sadece iki madde var.
We don't have access to match and so on there because while this is of course part of the routable
Elemeyi kabul etmiyoruz ve byle devam etmemiz gerekiyor nk bu tabii
area, burger is not loaded through a route object, only burger builder is. Burger builder is loaded through
Roudebush alannn bir paras iken burger bir rota nesnesi ile yklenmiyor, sadece burger burglarious burger Bolar bu rotaya
this route and everything which is loaded through a route but only the direct components, only burger
yklenecek ve her rota iin yklenmi olan her ey Sadece dorudan bileenler
builder itself gets these special props. Components nested inside burger builder
sadece Burgard Boulder'n kendisi Bergrin reticisi iinde yuvalanm bu zel sahne bileenlerini alr.
don't get them, we would have to pass them on manually.
Alma onlar elle gemek zorunda kalacaz.
There is a way we could still get the props in the burger component too though and this really is a
Yine de burger bileeni sahne almak iin bir yol var ve bu gerekten biraz gelimi
bit advanced and not something we need here
ve burada ihtiyacmz bir ey deil.
but I want to show it nonetheless.
Ama yine de gstermek istiyorum.
Let me reintroduce that log statement to see the props and we saw that we don't have the match and
Sorunu grmek iin bu kilit ifadeyi yeniden tantmamza izin verin ve eleme ve tarih
history thing.
olaymza sahip olmadn grdk.
If we use a special higher order component provided by react-router-dom, we can actually kind of inject
Yeniden hareket ynlendirici Dom tarafndan salanan zel bir yksek sipari bileeni kullanrsak, aslnda trden enjekte edebilir
or make them available, inject these special props in any component.
veya bunlar herhangi bir bileende enjekte edebilir hale getirebiliriz.
The higher order component is named withRouter and if we wrap our export with it, so like this with
Yksek sipari bileeni ynlendirici ile isimlendirilir ve ihracatmz Berger ynlendiricisi ile
router burger here, if I now save this
byle tamamlarsak, imdi unu kaydedelim.
now you see that in the router we also have match location and history and match will refer to the
ve eleen en yakn elemeye sahip olduumuzu gryoruz, bu yzden gemite eleen
nearest match. So to the nearest route which was matched in the past, in this case the route which matched
en yakn gzergaha, Bergere cesurluuna uyan gzergah da istediim bir ey. seninle payla
the burger builder. This is something I also wanted to share with you,
imdi ynlendiricide de eleme konumumuz ve gemii var
we will use it later again when we really need it,
Onu gerekten ihtiya duyduumuzda daha sonra tekrar kullanacaz.
just want to show this little trick.
Sadece bu kk numara gstermek istiyorum.
If you ever need direct access to match history and location and you don't want to manually pass
Herhangi bir lokasyondaki gemie eletirmek iin dorudan eriime ihtiyacnz varsa ve ynlendirici ile birlikte
it on from the top level component, you can use withRouter.
kullanabileceiniz en st dzeydeki bileenden manuel olarak gemek istemiyorsanz.
I did mention this in the routing section already.
Bunu zaten ynlendirme blmnde belirttim.
Well back to our original task, in the burger builder component, in the method which gets executed when
Bergere Boulder bileenindeki orijinal grevimize geri dnersek, orada devam et tklattmzda
we click continue, there.
idam edilen yntem.
I of course had access to this props,
Elbette bu sahneye eriebildim.
history is one of these special props provided by the router
Tarih, ynlendirici tarafndan salanan bu zel nlemlerden biridir.
and there we have this push prop which allows us to basically switch the page and push a new page onto that
Ve orada, temel olarak sayfalarn yn zerine sayfa yaptnz sayfa blmne gememizi
stack of pages.
salayan bu itme pervanesi var.
So now here I can simply say that I want to go to /checkout,
Dolaysyla imdi burada, basit bir ekilde kasay gzden geirmek istediimi syleyebilirim.
if we save this let's see what happens, if I start building my burger here and I click order now and
Bunu kaydedersek Bergere'yi buraya ekersem ne olacana bakalm ve imdi sipari ver ve devam
click continue,
et dmesine tklayn.
now I'm on the checkout page.
imdi deme sayfasnda bulunuyorum.
I get an error because the click listeners aren't hooked up yet
Dinleyiciler henz balanmam bir hata aldm.
but besides that, it's working. Now I won't connect
Fakat imdi alyor, bir balanmayacak.
this checkout navigation link here because I'm going to replace it with a my order soon anyways
Buradaki gezinme balantsna gz atmanz yeterli nk bunu hemen sipari ubuumla deitireceim, bu
so that's something I won't do here. But the next step I want to do is let's add more functionality so
yzden burada yapmayacam bir ey var ancak yapmak istediim sonraki adm, burada ptal'i tkladmzda
that when we click Cancel here, we actually are taken back.
daha fazla ilevsellik getirelim. biz aslnda geri alnr.
We go back to the burger builder whilst when clicking continue we show a form where we can enter
Berggruen Boulder'a geri dndmzde, devam etmeye tklarsak ona baz verileri girebileceimiz
some data.
yeri gsteriyoruz.
This is what I want to build next.
Srada byle yapmak istiyorum ite.